hostseo.org 2017-02-06

# SEO Hosting Terms of Service - HostSEO.org

### Philosophy

HostSEO places a priority on the data privacy of its customers, and on the importance of compliance with data privacy laws.

### Scope

The HostSEO Privacy Policy applies to customers who have provided identifiable sensitive personal or business data to HostSEO in the normal course of business. The data may be processed, stored, transferred or used as part of the customers potential, current or previous business relationship with HostSEO. You accept this policy when you sign up for our services or any other features, technologies or functionalities offered by our website or through any other means. 

This privacy notice applies solely to information collected by this web site. 

### Introduction

HostSEO places a priority on the data privacy of its customers and on the importance of compliance with applicable data privacy laws. This policy outlines and explains the appropriate principles concerning how HostSEO collects, processes, transfers, stores, and uses the sensitive data of covered customers. This policy covers the identifiable information of prospective, current, or former customers.

### Privacy Principles

The following data privacy principles form the foundation of the HostSEO Data Privacy Policy. As such, HostSEO will monitor the implementation of and adherence to these principles through appropriate management and controls on an ongoing basis. 

#### 1\. Notice 

HostSEO will inform customers about the purposes for which it collects data from them at any time to which it discloses data to third parties (as applicable and appropriate). Notice options will be provided as required by applicable laws and/or upon customer request. 

We are the sole owners of the information collected on this site. HostSEO will not sell or rent this information to anyone.

#### 2\. 3rd Party Transfer 

HostSEO is committed to protecting any sensitive data. Sensitive data regarding our customers will be transferred to third parties for processing outside of HostSEO only if the receiving party abides by privacy practices that provide an equivalent level of protection to these privacy policies. 3rd party transfers of customer data are to be limited to only those transfers necessary to facilitate the provision of the agreed services of HostSEO.

#### 3\. Security 

HostSEO is committed to protecting sensitive data of customers against unauthorized use or disclosure. HostSEO takes precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline. To prevent such unauthorized use or disclosure, HostSEO has put in place appropriate physical, technical, and organizational security measures.

Wherever sensitive information (such as credit card data) is collected, that information is encrypted and transmitted in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon at the bottom of your web browser, or looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the web page. HostSEO only utilizes 3rd party payment processing services that support comprehensive data retention security capabilities, such as PayPal and information about that security can be referenced at: https://www.paypal.com/us/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_security-center

#### 4\. Data Integrity 

HostSEO will take reasonable steps to verify that the sensitive customer data utilized by HostSEO is accurate, complete, relevant to the purpose and current and is processed in compliance with this policy. This web site contains thousands of links to other sites. Please be aware HostSEO is not responsible for the privacy practices of the sites to which we are linked. Please be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of any websites you visit.

#### 5\. Exceptions 

HostSEO recognizes that in certain limited circumstances, HostSEO may be required to deviate from the above policies and guidelines. Accordingly, HostSEO may be authorized additional disclosures under one of the following circumstances: 

When required by statute, regulation or contract; when required in response to administrative, judicial, or other legal process, including a document request, subpoena or search warrant; when required to cooperate with governmental agencies or law enforcement, to the extent permitted by local law; or when necessary to lawfully investigate and protect a legal or business interest of HostSEO.

Any exceptions are to be made with the recognition of the need for privacy balanced against the specific circumstances outlined above. 

#### 6\. Communications

Unless you ask us not to, we may contact you via email in the future to tell you about specials, new products or services, or changes to this privacy policy. We may amend this policy at any time by posting a revised version on our website.

#### 7\. Consensual Use

If HostSEO desires the use of your information for purposes exclusive of this privacy policy, you will be contacted for consent prior to its use.

#### 8\. Information Collection

If HostSEO desires the use of your information for purposes exclusive of this privacy policy, you will be contacted for consent prior to its use.

#### 9\. Information Collection

To correct personal information, address concerns over misuse of personal data or if you feel that we are not abiding by this privacy policy, please email us at contact[at]melen.net or call us at 201-870-6000.
